( theme music playing )
( crickets chirping )
Catelyn:
Are you sure about this?
No.
It's dangerous.
If we take Tywin's castle from him.
the lords of Westeros
will realize he's not invincible.
Take his home.
take his gold. take his power.
Why are you telling me?
You begged me not to send Theon
to negotiate with his father
and I ignored your advice.
Now Winterfell is burnt
to the ground.
the North is overrun with ironborn.
and Bran and Rickon are gone.
So Casterly Rock...
I'm asking your advice.
We have enough men?
If Walder Frey cooperates.
If reinforcements arrive
from King's Landing
before we take the castle...
we'll be caught between Tywin's army
and the sea.
We'll lose the war
and die the way Father died.
Or worse.
Show them how it feels
to lose what they love.
Walder:
My honored guests...
be welcome within my walls
and at my table.
I extend to you my hospitality
and protection
in the light of the Seven.
We thank you for your hospitality.
my lord.
I have come to make my apologies.
and to beg your forgiveness.
Don't beg my forgiveness. Your Grace.
It wasn't me you spurned.
It was my girls.
One of them was supposed to be queen.
Now none of them are.
This is Arwyen. my daughter.
My daughter Walda.
my daughter Derwa.
my daughter Waldra.
My eldest granddaughters
Ginia and Neila.
Serra and Sarra.
granddaughters. twins.
You could have had either.
Could have had both for all I care.
My granddaughter Marianne.
My granddaughter Freya.
My granddaughter... Wertha.
Waldra.
- Waldina.
- I'm Merry.
Fine.
And here's
my youngest daughter Shirei.
though she hasn't bled yet.
Clearly you don't have the patience
for all that.
My ladies. All men should keep
their word. kings most of all.
I was pledged to marry one of you
and I broke that vow.
The fault is not with you.
Any man would be lucky
to have any one of you.
I did what I did not to slight you.
but because I loved another.
I know these words cannot set right
the wrong I have done to you
and your house.
I beg your forgiveness
and pledge to do all I can
to make amends
so the Freys of the Crossing
and the Starks of Winterfell
may once again be friends.
Walder:
Very good.
There she is.
Come closer.
Let me have a look at you.
Still can't see you.
Old eyes.
Love.
That's what the Starks of Winterfell
call it. eh?
( chuckles )
Very honorable.
I call it a pretty face.
Mmm. very pretty.
Prettier than this lot.
that's for sure.
Very shapely as well.
Oh. you try to hide her
under that dress.
If you wanted to hide her.
you shouldn't have brought her here
in the first place.
I can always see
what's going on beneath a dress.
Been at this a long time.
I bet when you take that dress off.
everything stays right where it is.
Doesn't drop an inch.
Your king says
he betrayed me for love.
I say he betrayed me for firm tits
and a tight fit.
And I can respect that.
When I was your age.
I'd have broken 50 oaths
to get into that
without a second thought.
Well. I've enough room in the hall
for you lot.
We'll set up tents outside
with food and ale
for the rest of your men.
Thank you. my lord.
Well. let's get ready.
The wine will flow red
and the music will play loud
and we'll put this mess behind us.
- ( horse neighs )
- ( weapons clang )
- Where?
- There.
There. It's a back gate.
My men use it when they visit
Yunkai's bed slaves.
Your men. but not you?
Daario:
I have no interest in slaves.
A man cannot make love to property.
This is where we enter the city.
Very few guards. They know me.
They let me inside...
We're not gonna sneak an army
through a back gate.
I kill the guards.
I take your two best men
and lead them through the back
streets. which I know well.
and open the front gates.
Then comes the army.
Once the walls are breached.
the city will fall in hours.
Or perhaps you'll lead Grey Worm
and me to the slaughter.
cutting the head off our army.
The masters of Yunkai will pay you
your fee
and you won't have to split it
three ways
'cause you've already slaughtered
your partners.
You have a very suspicious mind.
In my experience.
only dishonest people think this way.
You command the Unsullied.
What do you think?
( Daenerys speaking Valyrian )
- You leave tonight.
- Very good.
We'll prepare.
Ser Jorah.
You can use an extra sword.
You're the Queensguard.
Ser Barristan.
Your place is by the queen.
If we are truly her loyal servants.
we'll do whatever needs to be done
no matter the cost.
no matter our pride.
We're west of Castle Black.
but the Nightfort's closest to us.
It was the first castle on the Wall.
The Watch abandoned it
during the reign of King Jaehaerys I.
Too big. Impossible to maintain.
Other than Castle Black itself.
the Nightfort's the perfect castle
for us.
It's got a secret sally port.
the Black Gate.
as old as the Wall itself.
No one's used it in centuries
most likely.
It leads through the Wall
right down into the Nightfort.
if one knows how to find it.
which. it just so happens. I do.
How do you know all that?
I read about it in a very old book.
You know all that
from staring at marks on paper?
Yes.
You're like a wizard.
Our father used to tell us
that no wildling ever looked
upon the Wall and lived.
Here we are.
Alive.
( donkey braying )
Remember what happens
to children who run.
I'm your father and I'll do the talking.
The roads have gone right to hell.
haven't they?
Cracked three spokes this morning.
- Need a hand?
- Need about eight hands.
Oh!
Got to get this salt pork
to the Twins
in time for the wedding.
Many thanks.
Don't! Don't kill him.
Dead rats don't squeak.
You're so dangerous. aren't you?
Saying scary things to little girls.
Killing little boys and old people.
A real hard man you are.
- More than anyone you know.
- You're wrong. I know a killer.
- A real killer.
- That so?
You'd be like a kitten to him.
He'd kill you with his little finger.
That him?
- No.
- Good.
Don't kill him. Please.
Please don't.
You're very kind.
Someday it'll get you killed.
( groaning )
( grunts )
Where are we?
The Gift. I think.
Brandon the Builder gave
all this land south of the Wall
to the Night's Watch
for their sustenance and support.
Maester Luwin taught me that.
Doesn't seem to be supporting
anyone at the moment.
It's good land
and there's no war up here.
Why leave?
Wildlings.
Sorry.
But they come over the Wall
and raid. steal. carry off women.
Old Nan said
they turn your skull into a cup
and make you drink your own blood
from it.
That's what Old Nan said.
There's a storm coming.
- I don't see any...
- ( thunder rolling )
It's as good a place to shelter
as any.
We can drink some blood
while we wait.
I don't need much.
( screeching )
Only one old man
and eight good horses.
What's one old man doing
with eight horses?
He breeds them for the Watch.
How's he keep folks
from stealing them?
The Watch protects him.
Not today they don't.
He's selling horses.
he's got some gold in there.
- Tormund: And proper steel.
- Let's carve him up.
We just take the horses and go.
The old man's no threat.
- I keep telling you.
- He's an old man.
A spear through the heart's
a better way to die
than coughing up your last
with no one but your horses to hear.
The Watch might send a few men
looking for a horse thief.
They'll send a lot more
to hunt down murderers.
I hope so.
Killing crows in their castle
is tough.
Killing them out here in the open.
that's what we do.
Spread out.
Surround the hut and move in.
- ( sword clangs )
- ( snorts )
( neighing )
Ygritte!
Man:
Clear the barn!
No one's going to believe you're
a hog farmer if you eat them all.
Best part of the animal.
- Don't worry. They're still there.
- I know they're still there.
You check every five minutes
like you're afraid
they're gonna move.
- I'm not afraid.
- Of course you are.
You're almost there
and you're afraid
you won't make it.
The closer you get.
the worse the fear gets.
No point in trying to hide
behind that face.
I know fear when I see it.
Seen it a lot.
I knew fear when I saw it in you.
You're afraid of fire.
When Beric's sword
went up in flames.
you looked like a scared little girl.
And I know why. too.
I heard what your brother did to you.
Pressed your face to the fire
like you're a nice juicy mutton chop.
That give you some ideas?
Might do.
Go ahead. then.
You might get away.
Might even make it there on your own.
They're just over the river.
The closest you've been to family
since Ilyn Payne snipped
your daddy's neck.
Someday I'm gonna put a sword
through your eye
and out the back of your skull.
( thunder rumbling )
( thunder crashes )
How are we going to get
past the Wall?
My uncle said it's 700 feet high.
( thunder crashes )
How did you get past it?
Got in a boat
and rowed past the Bay of Seals.
It would take us two months
to get to the Bay of Seals.
Some climb straight up the ice.
Even Hodor's not strong enough to
climb the Wall with me on his back.
Hodor.
- 19 castles guard the Wall.
- ( thunder booms )
- Only three are still manned.
- Hodor!
One of those abandoned fortresses
will give us a way through.
My uncle said the gates were sealed
with ice and stone
when the castles were deserted.
Well. we'll have
to open them up again.
( hoofbeats. horse neighs )
- Whoa. whoa. whoa!
- Meera: There's a rider out there.
- Just one?
- ( thunder crashes )
- Meera: There's more.
- Hodor!
( horses neighing )
Shh. Shh.
- It's just thunder. sweet giant.
- Hodor.
- Man: I yield. I yield.
- Wildlings.
( men shouting )
Where's Shaggydog and Summer?
- Hunting.
- ( horses neighing )
- ( thunder crashes )
- Hodor!
- Shh. quiet. Hodor.
Make him shut up.
If they hear us...
- Hush. Hodor. No more Hodoring.
- Hodor!
- Hodor. calm down.
- You need to keep quiet.
- They're gonna hear us.
- ( Hodor shouting )
- Bran: Hodor. be quiet.
( thunder crashes )
- Ah! Hodor!
- Hodor. calm down.
- Hodor! Hodor!
- Hodor. be quiet!
What did you do?
Nothing.
I don't know.
( horse screaming )
What's that?
That's a horse dying.
Man:
Bring them over here.
Man #2: That was the last of them.
The rest are dead.
Orell:
I heard shouting up there.
Thunder.
I know the difference
between shouting and thunder.
Maybe it's ghosts.
( laughs )
( eagle screeching )
That won't help you. grandpa.
- Where you riding?
- Doesn't matter now. does it?
No. it doesn't matter now.
Cut his throat
or he'll tell the crows we're here.
You understand.
Let me stand at least.
Let me go with a bit of dignity.
Make the crow kill him.
You're one of us now. Prove it.
The wolves are out there.
I can't do it by choice.
I don't know how.
It happens in my dreams.
You're a warg. Bran.
It's in your blood.
- I can't.
- You just did with him.
A wolf is nothing compared to that.
She looks sharp.
( muttering prayer )
Do it.
I told you.
He's still one of them.
Go on. boy.
Go on!
( groans )
He's a crow.
He'll always be a crow.
And here's his crow wife
guarding him.
He'll stab us in the back
first chance he gets.
- Kill him.
- ( Jon shouts )
( screaming )
- He's one of them.
- No!
Do you hear me?
( screams )
You're not gonna die
for one of them.
Do it.
They'll find us if you don't.
( swords clanging )
( breathing heavily )
( growling )
( Orell shouts )
( gasps )
You were right the whole time.
( eagle screeches )
( Jon screaming )
Hyah!
Daario: When you hear
a songbird's whistle. you come.
I'm a great whistler.
The greatest in the land.
- ( guard shouts in Valyrian )
- Daario Naharis.
( whistling )
Daario:
That one was quick.
- There may be others.
- I doubt it.
The Yunkish prefer to let their
slaves do their fighting for them.
( guards shouting )
That's what you call a few guards?
( men shouting )
Come on!
What do you got. huh?
( cheering )
Lord Edmure...
I hope I'm not a disappointment
to you.
( chuckles )
You're a delight to me. my lady.
You may now cloak the bride
and bring her under your protection.
In the sight of the Seven.
I hereby seal these two souls.
binding them as one for eternity.
Look upon each other
and say the words.
Both:
Father. Smith.
Warrior. Mother.
Maiden. Crone. Stranger...
- I am hers...
- I am his...
- and she is mine...
- and he is mine...
Both: ...from this day
until the end of my days.
- Is that safe?
- They're long gone.
You were right. I can get inside
Summer's mind whenever I want.
Of course you can.
North of the Wall there are wildlings
who can control all sorts of animals.
But you did a lot more than that.
You got inside Hodor's mind.
They can't do that north of the Wall?
No one can do that... anywhere.
When I was looking
through Summer's eyes. I saw Jon.
- Where?
- He was with the wildlings.
They tried to kill him.
but he got away.
Osha: He'll be heading back
to Castle Black. then.
That's where we should go.
For all we know.
Castle Black's already under attack.
If this many wildlings got through
I already told you.
I'm not going north of the Wall.
Everything Jojen told me is true.
You saw what I did to Hodor.
I have to find the three-eyed raven.
Listen to me. little lord.
Don't worry.
I'm not asking you to come with me.
It won't be safe for Rickon.
Me? I'm coming with you.
No.
You and Osha and Shaggydog
head for the Last Hearth.
The Umbers are our bannermen.
They'll protect you.
I'm coming with you.
I'm your brother.
I have to protect you.
Right now I have to protect you.
Robb's at war
and I'm going beyond the Wall.
If something happens to us.
you're the heir to Winterfell.
Would you know
how to find the Last Hearth?
You southerners build
your big castles and you never move.
You're easy to find.
We're not southerners.
And I don't want to leave you.
Shh. shh.
Come here. little soldier.
You and me.
we're gonna have some adventures.
You don't have to do any of this.
( crying )
Your family took me in
and was good to me
when they had no cause to be.
Shh. We'll be fine. you and me.
The Umbers are great warriors.
Even I heard about them growing up.
They'll teach you
how to swing a sword.
I know how to swing a sword.
( kisses )
You're leaving now?
It's the middle of the night.
I learned to walk in darkness.
Say your good-byes. little man.
Keep this one safe.
He means the world to me.
We've been waiting a long time.
Haven't we?
I don't know. you tell me.
How long does it take to sack a city?
It was just as you said.
They did not believe
until it was too late.
Their slave soldiers threw down
their spears and surrendered.
And Daario Naharis?
( footsteps )
The city is yours. my queen.
( music playing )
( people laughing. chatting )
They're good. aren't they?
They ought to be
because they cost enough.
( laughs )
- Look at the crowd there.
- ( Catelyn laughs )
He complained about this marriage
the entire ride from Riverrun.
and now look at him.
Blackfish:
The gods love to reward a fool.
- Uncle.
- What?
He's my nephew. I love him.
And he's a damned fool.
( chuckles )
Don't you drink. Lord Bolton?
Never do. my lady.
Dulls the senses.
That's the point.
Didn't you marry
one of these Frey girls?
Aye.
Lord Walder let me
choose any of his granddaughters
and promised me the girl's weight
in silver as a dowry.
So I have a fat young bride.
( laughs )
I hope she makes you very happy.
Well. she's made me very rich.
Pardon. my lord. my lady.
I need to find a tree to piss on.
My mother's alone with Roose Bolton.
I should rescue her.
Your mother is less in need of rescue
than any woman I've ever met.
Be kind.
She's finally starting to like you.
And I like her.
But if she had her way.
I would be back in Volantis
playing my harp
and you would be sitting over there
eating blackberries
out of Roslin Frey's hand.
Perhaps I've made
a terrible mistake.
( scoffs )
Striking your king
is an act of treason.
No. don't.
Don't insult them.
Your Grace.
( pounding on tables )
( pounding stops )
The septon has prayed his prayers.
some words were said.
and Lord Edmure has wrapped
my daughter in a cloak.
But they are not yet
man and wife.
A sword needs a sheath.
( guests laughing )
( laughs )
And a wedding needs a bedding.
( guests cheering )
What does my sire say?
( guests chanting )
To bed! To bed! To bed!
If you think the time is right.
Lord Walder.
by all means. let us bed them.
( guests cheering )
( music playing )
( chanting )
To bed! To bed! To bed!
Man:
Go on!
Oh! Careful now. ladies.
Once you set that monster free.
there's no caging him again.
( chanting continues )
To bed! To bed! To bed!
Poor girl.
Every bride suffers the same.
I'm sure
you endured yours with grace.
Oh. Ned forbade it.
He said it wouldn't be right
if he broke a man's jaw
on our wedding night.
( chuckles )
That is a very strange custom.
I suppose it does seem strange
from a foreigner's perspective.
- It seems normal to you?
- It's a tradition.
Without the bedding ceremony.
there's no real proof
the lord and lady consummated
their marriage.
But there are other ways
of providing proof.
Boy or girl?
I don't know.
But if it's a boy.
I know what we should name him.
Oh. do you?
It seems to me the father should have
some say in his son's naming.
Eddard.
Don't you want to teach
little Ned Stark how to ride horses?
I do.
( band playing
"Rains of Castamere" )
( wolf whining )
( whines )
Man:
Go on. line 'em up!
( chatter. laughter )
( laughing )
Whoa. whoa. whoa. whoa.
- Where are you going?
- Got salt pork for the feast.
The feast is over.
Hound:
Doesn't sound like it's over.
If I tell you it's over. it's over.
Turn this cart around
and get the hell out of here.
Got pig's feet. too.
Are you soft in the head?
Turn this cart around.
( music stops )
Your Grace.
I feel I've been remiss in my duties.
I've given you meat
and wine and music.
but I haven't shown you
the hospitality you deserve.
My king has married and I owe
my new queen a wedding gift.
Robb!
( gasping )
( grunts )
( screams continue )
( screaming )
( men laughing )
Stark soldier: You ready
to head home to Winterfell. right?
( men laughing )
Stark soldier:
Feast over yet. is it?
Aye. it's over.
( men screaming )
( wolf howling )
- ( banging )
- ( growling )
( growling )
Guard:
Follow him.
- Aim!
- ( snarling )
( growls )
( wolf whines )
( guard shouting )
( groaning )
( guards shouting )
It's too late.
- ( grunting )
- ( fighting continues )
( chuckles )
The King in the North arises.
Lord Walder!
Lord Walder. enough!
Let it end!
Please.
He is my son.
My first son.
Let him go and I swear
that we will forget this.
I swear it
by the old gods and new.
We will take no vengeance.
You already swore me one oath
right here in my castle.
You swore by all the gods
your son would marry my daughter!
Catelyn: Take me for a hostage.
but let Robb go.
Robb. get up.
Get up and walk out. Please!
Please!
And why would I let him do that?
On my honor as a Tully.
on my honor as a Stark.
let him go
or I will cut your wife's throat.
I'll find another.
Mother.
The Lannisters send their regards.
( knife pierces )
( wails )
( knife clatters )